the side, welcome back. So, in the
previous part, we have already
understood the stream
Kafka stream architecture.
Very, very important. Okay?
Now, what we will do today is that we
will do setup of the Kafka stream and
also double-check our understanding that
it matches what we understood as an
architecture.
So, in architecture, we understood about
topology,
sub-topology,
task,
repartition,
and change log, right? So, we will
double-check with our setup.
So, the first thing is dependency. We
will have to add a dependency. So, I
told you that Kafka stream is nothing
but a jar.
So, apart from Kafka,
we just need to add a Kafka stream jar.
Kafka \hyphen} streams. That's all.
Second thing is application.properties.
So, here if you see,
I told you that Kafka stream is built on
top of Kafka consumer architecture or
framework. So, very similar to Kafka
consumer itself. Define a port,
name, and you have to define a streams
application ID. So, consider that as a
like a group ID.
Like in consumer, we define a group ID,
right? Similarly, consider that as a
group ID, application ID.
I have given order \hyphen} analytics.
Then the bootstrap server, because it
has to fetch the metadata, so it needs
somebody to connect to.
Then, how many number of stream
properties, stream threads? So, how many
number of stream processing instances
you need to create in this application.
I created two, so two instances will get
created.
Okay? So, tasks will be divided among
these two instances.
So, each task creates a RocksDB file,
right? So, where that file will get
stored?
Streams properties state.directory dir
/temp/kafka-streams.
You can give any name. So,
the at this path, the file of the Rocks
DB would get stored on local disk.
Very minimal application.properties I
have written.
The third is like in your application,
you have to just set @EnableKafkaStreams
annotation, so that it will uh enable
all the beans or it will load all the
streams Kafka streams related beans for
us.
And the fourth,
we have to define the topology. I told
you that all we have to is tell the
topology.
Okay?
After that, everything is handled by the
framework.
Okay, we don't have to deal with change
log. We don't have to deal with
repartition. We don't have to deal with
sub topologies. All we have to write is
topology.
Okay? So, now let's say here I have
created one topology. Again,
don't worry about the syntax at all
because syntax we will go later.
How to create a stream, different
processors, we will see that.
At this point of time, we are just
setting up and double-check our
understanding with the architecture. So,
topology I have created.
So, the source
So, you remember, right? Topology we
will have is like
source
source topic
Then after that, you have processors,
different processors which can have
let's say step one, step two, step
three.
And after that, you can have a sink
topic.
Okay?
So, this is my source. So, read from
order-events. So, this is our
source topic.
Source
topic.
Now, these are the processor. One is
filter.
Filter
greater than 100. So, this is filter.
Greater than 100.
Okay? It has to filter the orders.
Now, here our repartition. So, we are
repartition based on product ID.
Okay? So, this is we are doing
repartition
based on
product ID.
Okay?
After that, we are storing some info
into the
So, we are doing group by key.
So, next task we are doing is group
by key
and also count. So, we are storing into
the RocksDB also.
So, count.
So, count it stores into the
RocksDB. The RocksDB name we have given
is product-count-store.
Product-count-store.
This is our RocksDB file name.
Okay?
And ultimately, the output topic is
this, product-counts. This is our
output topic.
Okay? So, our topology which we have
created is
if you uh
just write it.
So, here I have created the topology.
The topology is order- events. Source is
order-events.
Do a filter greater than 100.
Repartition based on product ID.
Group by the key.
Then count. So, in the count, we have to
store
maintain a state. So, we will maintain a
state in the RocksDB. RocksDB name we
have given is product-count-store.
And ultimately, we have to put into the
output topic, which is product-counts.
Okay? So, this is the topology which we
have created.
And this is the Kafka cluster which has
topic order events
which is three partition. Partition
zero, partition one, partition
P2, three partition.
Okay, so producer produce into this
order events.
Okay, and this is the topology which we
have created.
Now,
stop at this point of time.
And from this topology,
I want you to create
all the sub topology
plus all the different topics which will
get created into the Kafka cluster.
So now let's go ahead.
So, let's see what all sub topology it
will create.
So, sub topology zero, source is order
events. Filter greater than 100. Now at
this point of time repartition happen.
Repartition based on product ID. So,
it's what it will do, it will sink into
repartition topic.
So, it will create a
And the same number of partition which
source has. Order event has three
partition, so it will also have three
partitions.
Then sub topology one, it will read from
this repartition topic.
Then after that,
group by key,
count,
the RockDB has this
product counter store. Okay, and
ultimately output topic is product
counts.
So, RockDB also maintain a change log
topic. So, there would be product count
store change log
topic.
This is a change log topic.
How many partition it will have?
This will have the same number of
partition which this source partition
have. So, its source topic has
three.
That's why it will also have three
partition.
Okay? So, everything depend upon the
source partition.
Now, output topic is product count. So,
let's say this topic which we have
already created, it can have more number
of partition, it can have less number of
partitions. Okay, depends. So, let's say
output topic product hyphen count. So,
our producer or some other application
or
external, we this topic is already
created. All we are doing is we are just
dumping the event into this topic. So,
it can have
partition P0, P1, P2, P3, P4, P5 or P0,
P1 only. Different number of partition I
wanted to say.
Okay? So, we have created
two sub topology.
Okay? And uh
repartition change log will get created.
Now, task. How many task would get
created? So, for this sub topology,
it sources order events. So, order event
has three partitions, so three task.
So, 0 underscore 0. 0 is like sub
topology 0.
Order event partition P0.
Order event partition P1. Order event
partition P0 for this sub topology.
Similarly, for this sub topology, it
sources repartition. So, it's
repartition has three partition.
So, three task is required.
Sub topology one, one one.
Sources repartition topic, partition P0,
partition P1, partition P2. P2.
So, total six task is created.
And
we have in the application.properties,
we have defined two instances, right?
So, this six task
this six task will get assigned to two
instances
or two thread. Thread one, thread two.
Or our instance is only one but two
threads. So this task
will get assigned. Let's say task one,
task two, task three, task four, task
five, task six to thread two. Like this.
So this three task will get divided to
these two threads.
So this is the ultimately
expectation which we have to double
check. So let's test.
Okay, so same thing I so
in the Kafka stream application I have
just added this dependency
application.properties
a Kafka enable Kafka streams annotation
and I have defined this topology.
Okay.
Now we have to do the testing.
Now let's see that.
Okay, so here
just showing you the Kafka stream demo.
So this is my topology. The same thing.
Exactly the same thing. I have added the
annotation
and here application.properties.
Okay, nothing differs.
Now first thing we have to do is we have
to
start the Kafka cluster
and also start the Kafka producer app.
So now let me first start it and also I
will just properly clean everything so
that it don't have any old data. So
remove all the logs like we used to do
before.
Okay, the second thing is we will create
a new unique ID UUID.
Okay, and all the clusters
brokers, controller brokers we will
assign with this, attach with this ID
now.
Controller one.
Controller two.
Broker one.
>> [clears throat]
>> Just a sec.
Invalid cluster ID. Cluster ID is this
only, right?
Mhm. I think it's not removed yet.
Let's remove.
Okay, broker one has to be removed,
right? So, let's remove broker one.
Similarly, broker two need to be
removed. Okay. Now, let's
add broker one dot properties.
Broker two dot properties.
So, in our we have created a new
cluster. In that two cluster, we have
added two controllers, two brokers.
Now, we have to start those.
So, we have to start those clusters and
brokers.
So,
the command to start them is
Yeah.
This is controller one for this is for
controller
two.
So, let's just start this. Let's just
start this.
Similarly, let's just start
broker one.
Let's just start broker
two.
So, broker two started, broker one
started, controller started, both the
controller are started.
Okay?
So, everything is started here.
So, now let's just start producer. So,
we already have this producer
application. I have already shared the
Git also.
So, I am just
running it up.
So, our producer is also started. And
when our producer is started, it should
have created
order \hyphen} events with three
partitions.
So, we can check that. So, till now
we have started the Kafka cluster, we
have started the Kafka producer app.
Okay? So, here
started Kafka producer application is
done. So, at this point of time is done.
So, now we can use this command
to know.
We can describe the events. Let's see.
So, we can describe this topic order
\hyphen} events. So, here if you see
Let me zoom it a bit.
I hope it's clearly visible.
So, here
order \hyphen} events topic is created
which has three partition.
Partition zero is
leader is four.
Partition one leader is three. Partition
two leader is four.
So,
here if you see
so we have
broker
one broker two brokers, right? Broker
two.
So, broker one has ID three
and broker two has ID four.
Because we also have controller one
controller two, it has given ID one, it
has given ID two, broker one ID three,
broker two ID four. Okay? So, now two
broker three partition. So, broker one
broker one has here
partition one. It's a leader of
partition one and ID four. Broker two is
leader of partition zero and two.
So, currently this is working fine.
Okay? So, let me also return here so
that uh
broker one has leader of partition one,
partition zero, and partition two.
Okay?
Now,
we will see that what all
topics present at this point of time.
Okay, I'm just running the command
hyphen hyphen list. Here if you see only
one order hyphen events, that's all.
Nothing much.
Okay? So, here
just a sec.
Okay. So, this is uh currently the
producer, right? So, currently order
hyphen event is present.
So, at this point of time this should
not get internally created.
Okay? So, let me check that once we
start the stream,
because a stream also has your Kafka
consumer also, then it should have
created it. Now, let's see that.
So, currently
now I'm starting the Kafka stream
here.
So, now let's start a Kafka stream
application. Run.
Let's see. Does it created?
See, it now created this all.
So,
after I run the Kafka stream
application,
what it does is
we have Kafka consumer offset.
Okay? Kafka consumer offset.
Order even was already there before.
Now, it has created repartition and
change log.
Okay? Why? Because based on our
topology,
based on our topology,
it has created a repartition.
Okay? So, repartition
it has created, and it also have uh
change log for our
RocksDB.
Okay?
So, the name it has given is uh the
group name, order \hyphen} analytics.
And then product \hyphen} count \hyphen}
store repartition. Like product \hyphen}
count \hyphen} store
uh \hyphen} change log will also be
there.
And the name repartition topic name also
it has choose this one. The group name,
and the same name it has used.
And after that, it has put repartition.
So, it also has created a repartition
topic also.
So, this is all done.
Now,
so till here we are done.
So, all these four topics now present.
Now, we need to see
which task assigned to which instance.
So, we have two instances two thread
created, right? So, two thread means
two stream
processing
instance are running. So, the total six
task should have created.
Total six task should have created based
on our understanding.
So, for this sub topology three task,
for this sub topology three task, total
six. And this six task should be divided
among our
two instances.
Okay? So, now let's see run and see this
one.
So, what I'm just doing is that
here
if you see
group is order analytics. So, I'm just
describing the group. Okay? Group is
order analytics. Now, here if you see
order analytics product count and store
repartition.
Okay? So,
this is repartition partition one.
So, I think it's difficult to read it
from here, but I will show you like from
here when I just uh
minimize it a bit
and just increase it, it will all come
into one single line. Then it would be
easier to read. So, you read it from
here like this. It would be easy to
understand.
So, group is order analytics.
The topics.
Okay? So, now we have six tasks, right?
So, task one
here if you see
your task one
is reading
source order events partition P0.
Okay?
Similarly, some other task would be like
source is repartition partition P0.
Like this it will happens.
The same thing is there only.
So, here if you see
So, total three partitions, right? So,
one let's say for repartition partition
one
partition two
partition zero. So, zero one two three
partition
uh
is getting read by three task.
Okay? Similarly, order hyphen events
partition one
partition zero
partition two.
So, three task are reading these three
partitions.
Okay? And now here if you see
instances
So, stream thread two stream thread two
stream thread two. So, this
first three
first three are read by
thread
two.
And the last three are read by
thread one.
Thread one thread one thread one.
Okay?
So, repartition zero
repartition
partition number zero is read by thread
one. Similarly, order event
partition zero
reads by thread one. Order event
partition P2 read by thread one. So
total six task
thread one has owned these three task
thread two owns these three task.
So, clear? That's our expectation also.
Our expectation also we have said this
thing only.
So, here if you see in our expectation
we also said that three task.
For repartition partition zero partition
one partition two. Similarly, for order
event partition zero partition one,
partition two. The same thing it's
there.
Okay? So, six tasks
three for each thread.
So, now let's publish an event.
So, now let's say I'm publishing an
event.
Okay?
Let's publish an event. Order created
event published. So, here if you see
producer application
uh
order event sent successfully partition
zero and partition two this event got
ultimately published.
So,
we can check that again.
So, partition P0
So, here if you see
hm
let's
check that.
So, [snorts] temporary broker one. So,
here if you see
partition P0. Who is the leader for
partition P0 for order events?
So, we have written that one, right? So,
during the start
P0
is broker two.
So,
let's run it.
Broker two.
So, all we this is broker two \hyphen}
logs
>> [snorts]
>> \slash} order \hyphen} events \slash}
zero partition zero. Let's check it.
So, here
we have this event.
Right? Key is order \hyphen} one. This
is the key.
Okay? So, this got published.
So, one thing is clear that our
publishing is works.
So, till now we are done at this point
of time.
Producer application log is done and
also we have seen the logs of order
hyphen zero.
This one.
Partition P0 it goes, right? So, this
thing is coming.
So, now
once the data
has been published to order events,
we know that what would have happened.
So, our stream sub topology zero.
So, our task, right?
Which is reading the partition P0.
Might have picked. Okay? And it will run
the task. So, it will do just filter and
then repartition and it will output into
the repartition topic.
Okay? So, now data might have gone into
the repartition. So, repartition also
has three partitions. So, in which
partition it goes, we don't know.
Depending upon the key, the data will
go. So, we have to check.
So, we are just dumping
order hyphen analytics hyphen product
count to store repartition zero.
We don't know that repartition Earlier,
we know that when the event is
published,
when the event was published, it goes
into partition P0 of the order hyphen
event. But after repartition based on
the product ID, whether it goes to the
partition P0 or partition P1 or
partition P2, we don't know.
Okay? So, that's why
we can check all three. So, I'm just
checking partition P0 first.
So, yeah. Seems data is present here.
So, if you check partition one, it there
would be no data.
There would be no data.
Okay? So, it goes into P0 itself.
Here.
So, data goes into the P0 itself and
here we can check the key.
What So, the key is now product ID.
Okay? And the when when the data was
here in the
order-events
when it was there in the order-event key
was
key was order ID.
Okay? So, check this. These are small
small things, but these things helps to
like clarify our things. So, when the
event was published
here
the key was
order ID, O-1.
Okay? After repartition in
the same payload but the key is now
product ID.
Okay? So, we got to know that the
repartition topic also is getting the
data.
Now, let's check the RockDB local. So,
here if you see
that
path which we have given in
application.properties like
/temp/kafka-streams.
So,
temp
kafka-streams
here if you see order analytics, your
application name.
Now,
for all six
for all the task, each task means
maintain its own
RockDB file.
So,
00, can you read it?
Sub-topology zero, partition P0.
Sub-topology zero, partition P1.
Sub-topology zero, partition P2.
Sub-topology one, partition P0.
Sub-topology one, partition P1.
Sub-topology one, partition P2. Now,
which topic from the sub-topology we
know that it's order-events.
From sub-topology one, we know that it's
a repartition topic.
So, order-events P0, order-events P1,
P2. Similarly, repartition topic P0,
repartition topic P1, similar P2.
Okay, so each task is maintained the
Rock DB slash whatever the name which we
have given
and the file it maintain.
You can't open and read it because it's
in binary, but it's a key value.
Key is let's say
process ID
one
value is let's say
order you might have got is like 50
orders till now for this one.
Okay.
One more event comes for this process ID
one, it will get incremented
like this.
Okay. So, you can easily check it. Like
you can go to the temp Kafka streams
order analytics.
Now here if you see six events, for each
events goes to Rocks DB
particular store and then check it.
Okay.
I told you that for each like Rock DB is
backed up by the change log topic. So,
change log topic is already there. We
can also see that one.
So.
Instead of repartition, we have
change log. So, repartition zero data
goes into change log zero only.
Okay, the same thing.
So, change log data is also coming.
Okay. Similarly, the output you can also
check like the same thing.
I hope everything is now clear, right?
No such file or exception product hyphen
counts. So, it might have gone through
the broker one.
Which is in broker two.
Let's check broker one has got this.
Yep.
So, output is also going.
Okay? So, I hope this is clear like
we are able to set up properly.
We have checked the output topic. We
have checked the change log topic. We
have checked the raw DB. The file is
present.
Okay? The repartition
uh
like we have seen the normal like uh
earlier what we have seen producer and
everything we have set up.
Task distribution among the threads.
Okay? So, this is I want to cover as a
part of setup.
So, this is important, right? So, I
think
our architecture Kafka stream
architecture should be clear.
And using that architecture
understanding
the setup which we have done very simple
setup
of this topology. Yeah. So, I would say
that for this topology, we have done the
setup.
All we have written is this topology.
Internally, this is all internal
internal internal. This is all happen
internal. All it is visible is this
topology. All we have to write is
source, filter, this all this thing.
But after that what happened
that is something which need to be clear
to us.
And if we have to be very efficient in
the streams.
Okay?
So, if you understand sub topology,
right? Then the naming convention task 0
_ 0. You don't have to be like confused
like what 0 is 0. You know that it's 0
first 0 is like for the sub topology.
Task 1 _ 0 is like sub topology. There
could be sub sub topology one.
Okay? Then you can check your topology
that okay, how it have created a
different sub topologies.
Okay?
Cool.
Okay? Any doubt in this setup?
Again
agenda is not that we are clear with the
syntax. Agenda is not like what the
syntax does. Dot group by key, what it
does. No.
Agenda here is that whatever the
architecture understanding we had,
we do a setup
and we validate the same thing.
Okay?
Okay, guys. Thank you. Bye.
Any doubt, let me know in the comment
section.
Thank you.